### Hello.

# I'm Julia Pauletti

Plano, TX 75024 (469) 463-7528 julia.pauletti@yahoo.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/juliapauletti/

Github: github.com/jpauletti

Portfolio: jpauletti.github.io/Portfolio

## **Summary**

Full Stack Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in development and UX design. Experience working with multiple clients on various projects at the same time. Passionate about blending design and functionality. Values communication and enjoys collaborative working environments. Certified in Full Stack Web Development, including skills in React, Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, and AWS. Ready to take on both front-end and server-side challenges with advanced design skills and steadfast problem-solving abilities.

#### Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, React, Git, Node.js, Express, AWS, Firebase, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, jQuery, Handlebars, Litmus, Silverpop, Sketch, Invision, Site Maps, Wireframes, User Journeys/Flows

# **Experience**

SEPT 2019 - PRESENT

### Dynata, Plano, TX - Software Engineer

Design and implement full user experiences using web technologies. Communicate within team on architectural approaches, design, and coding. Author and manage technical documentation to support delivery, maintenance, and adoption. Design and develop automated deployment mechanisms. Provide regular demonstrations on deliverables within and outside the engineering team.

- Maintain multiple codebases, including major feature updates and bug fixes. Built with a variety of technologies including React, web components, and Node.js.
- Integrate with AWS services including DynamoDB, CloudFront, Lambda, CodeBuild, RDS and Aurora, CLI, and CloudWatch.

JULY 2017 - SEPT 2019

### Commerce House, Dallas, TX - UX Designer/Front-End Developer

Work with clients on a variety of digital projects while collaborating with account managers, strategists, designers, and developers to provide clients with a high-quality final product.

- Design site maps and wireframes using data about how users navigate the site. Develop information architecture using site analytics and best practices, creating a well-organized site structure that is intuitive for the user. Create user journeys and user flows to ensure a consistent experience for the user.
- Produce HTML email campaigns (100+) including testing in Litmus and Silverpop. Develop banner ads using Google Web Designer and GreenSock. Collaborate with the development team from conception to project launch; assist with site maintenance, troubleshooting, and updates post-launch to ensure 100% client satisfaction. Manage site content, set up, and conduct client training.

## Julia Pauletti

## **Experience (continued)**

FEB 2017 - JULY 2017

YourCause, Plano, TX - Product & Strategy Designer

Innovated user experience design across web applications utilizing user and use-case research, UX architecture, and UI design. Worked within existing style guides and patterns while continuing to push the envelope for better user experiences.

- Coordinated closely with account managers, product managers, and engineers to ensure smooth delivery, maximized team collaboration and the highest possible product quality.
- Developed low and high fidelity prototypes as well as final visual design deliverables.

AUG 2016 - FEB 2017

#### Ryon's Web Design, Allen, TX - Web Marketing & Design

Create and maintain websites and their SEO using Wordpress. Designed mock-ups of websites for new clients.

- Managed multiple projects at once including troubleshooting, communicating with clients, and keeping a consistent brand across the company's online presence.
- Moved content from old sites to new, adjusting for new content structures, and making updates as needed.

#### Education

AUG 2019

#### Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX - Full Stack Web Development

24-week intensive program learning skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars, React.js, Git, Heroku, MySQL, MongoDB, and Express.

MAY 2016

UT Dallas, Richardson, TX - Emerging Media & Communication

Graduated Cum Laude with a GPA of 3.779.

# **Projects**

Word Guess Game https://jpauletti.github.io/Word-Guess-Game

The theme is Billboard Hot 100 song titles from 2019. Guess a letter by typing it - each time you guess a letter correctly, it will appear in the word until you've guessed the entire song title or run out of guesses.

Built with: HTML, CSS, and VanillaJS.

WordTris | https://wordtris.herokuapp.com

Like Tetris + Scrabble combined! 3 letters fall from the top of the screen, and you place them on the board to make words. Each letter has a number of points assigned to it, so each word you successfully make will add to your score.

<u>My Role</u>: Main design and color scheme, set up pages and components, user authentication, parts of game logic, logic for sending front-end data to database, cross-browser support.

Built with: React, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Express Session, React Move, and Trie.